<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moodle Plugin on IMI Showtime</title>
    <link>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moodle Plugin on IMI Showtime</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Architecture</title>
      <link>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Overview&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/architecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;Project Architecture&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Moodle System Architecture&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        Plugins must follow &lt;strong&gt;Moodle’s technical and organisational guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; to qualify for the official plugin directory. Moodle consists of its core with different subsystems and a substantial amount of plugins. These plugins need to be of a specific type. For our plugins these are quiz report and question behaviour. A clear type assignment is essential, because only plugins with an unambiguous type can be correctly installed or published.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Existing Plugins&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        The standard installation of Moodle already offers a number of question behaviours for tests. &lt;strong&gt;Immediate Feedback&lt;/strong&gt; adds a “Check” button after a question so learners can submit each answer and see right away whether it is correct, together with any configured feedback. &lt;strong&gt;Deferred Feedback&lt;/strong&gt; hides that button, letting students finish the whole quiz first and revealing correctness and review feedback only after they click “Submit all and finish.” During the research, plugins from the Moodle plugin directory were also identified that are functionally similar to the planned plugin.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Difficulty Assessment Plugins&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        The Student Review plugins extend Moodle’s question behaviour, which controls how students interact with quiz questions. Like other behaviour plugins, they are stored under question/behaviour/ and follow Moodle’s plugin conventions, including metadata in version.php, translations in lang/, and frontend logic via amd/ JavaScript modules. We provide two variants of this plugin. Student Review Deferred integrates with the “Deferred Feedback” mode and optionally shows a difficulty rating scale after a question is completed. Student Review Immediate builds on the deferred variant, but also enforces a rating before feedback is shown, using Moodle’s standard “Check” button workflow. Both plugins include rendering templates (renderer.php) and behaviour logic (behaviour.php) to control visibility, interactivity, and data collection. Ratings are stored using Moodle’s internal database structure and are linked to the student’s quiz attempt for later retrieval.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Analysis plugin&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        In order to evaluate student difficulty ratings, a custom report plugin was developed that integrates with Moodle&amp;rsquo;s existing quiz reporting system. The plugin is of the quiz report type, where it is accessible in the standard results section of every Moodle quiz. The system utilises SQL queries across multiple Moodle database tables to establish a correlation between ratings and question IDs, names, and content. The plugin presents these results directly in Moodle using html_writer for clean rendering and offers a downloadable CSV via Moodle&amp;rsquo;s download_data function. This design keeps data structured, secure, and consistent with Moodle’s built-in export tools.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges</title>
      <link>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Moodle&amp;#39;s Documentation&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        In the early stages of the project we found that Moodle’s official plugin documentation was &lt;strong&gt;incomplete and occasionally outdated&lt;/strong&gt;. This issue complicated our analysis of the platform architecture and the placement of our own plugins. We therefore had to take a look at existing plugins and figure out the structure ourselves. Due to challenges encountered with the documentation, a non-standard plugin was found that delivered some of the intended features later in the project. This &lt;strong&gt;strategic realignment&lt;/strong&gt; involved revising the schedule and re-engineering the solution around these proven capabilities.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Ensuring a Robust Solution&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        Our primary objective was to deliver a &lt;strong&gt;robust, production-ready solution&lt;/strong&gt; in time for the next semester. The core functionality is stable, and the plugin has been designed to integrate smoothly into Moodle’s workflow. However, Moodle’s extensive configuration options and gaps in its documentation meant that certain issues came to light late in the development process. Furthermore, the team&amp;rsquo;s limited experience with the platform&amp;rsquo;s administrative interface, in addition to the notable differences between our test server and the HTW Moodle environment, made it challenging to ensure seamless compatibility across all Moodle installations. These experiences highlighted the importance of close coordination with our supervisors and their expertise. While the plugin works reliably under standard conditions, further testing and feedback from real-world use will help refine edge cases and improve long-term maintainability.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Testing&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        The plugin successfully passed all internal tests on our dedicated Moodle test server. Its core functionality worked reliably across multiple test scenarios. This confirms that the implementation is technically sound and ready for use under standard Moodle configurations. However, a key limitation in the testing process was the lack of direct access to the HTW production instance. As a result, we were unable to validate the plugin in the exact environment in which it would ultimately be deployed. This led to some unexpected setup difficulties for our stakeholders, caused by configuration differences between our test system and their live Moodle instance. For future development, we recommend early-stage coordination with system administrators and direct testing within the target Moodle environment. This will help identify environment-specific issues early on and ensure a truly seamless deployment experience.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            General&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        Teachers can &lt;strong&gt;choose to enable student reviews&lt;/strong&gt; for their tests. Installing the plugins does not mean they will be used for every test. Teachers can turn the feature on and off for each test they create. If this feature is activated, students will be asked to rate the difficulty of questions. Once a question in a test has been rated by the student, it won’t be eligible for review anymore. The review will be displayed at the end of the question and consists of a heatbar with review options from easy to very difficult. All feedback is collected anonymously to ensure honest and unbiased responses. The student review should not be performed for all questions, but only for a proportion of them, in order to keep the load as low as possible. For each question, a random number between 0 and 1 is generated at the beginning of the test attempt. The questions for which the numbers are between 0 and 0.5 are then selected for a student review. From this, it can be deduced that students may not have to evaluate any tasks in a test. It is also possible that all tasks can be evaluated.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Student Review Deferred&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        There are two versions of the assessment function: deferred and immediate. This allows for flexible use of the function, depending on didactic requirements. In the deferred version, submitting a difficulty assessment is optional. This is because students do not receive feedback on the content of their assignment until they have answered all the questions in the test. This means that students cannot be &amp;lsquo;forced&amp;rsquo; to submit a rating. However, it is also possible to rate the level of difficulty even if the question has not been answered. This is because if the question is not answered, students may still perceive it as very difficult and provide relevant feedback.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Student Review Immediate&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        With the &amp;lsquo;Immediate&amp;rsquo; variant, students receive immediate feedback on the content of their question when they click the &amp;lsquo;Check&amp;rsquo; button. After that, the entry cannot be changed. With the Student Review Immediate plugin, the difficulty of the question is queried afterwards, as with the deferred variant. The difference from the deferred version is that students must submit a rating to receive feedback on their answer to the quiz question. This is intended to encourage students to evaluate the questions in order to receive content-related feedback.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Student Report&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        Teachers can view and export data for further use in the quiz reports. For each question in a test, key metrics such as the average and median of the given ratings are calculated and presented in a report. The calculations are based exclusively on the anonymised student reviews and make it possible to identify questions that students consider particularly easy or difficult. In addition to these metrics, information such as the internal question name, the question text, general feedback and the associated question ID is also displayed in the report. An export function is provided for further analysis or archiving. The data can be exported to CSV, PDF, HTML table, JSON, Excel and ODS format.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Stack</title>
      <link>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/techstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/techstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Organization&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/&#34;&gt;Gitlab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for code collaboration and distribution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://miro.com/&#34;&gt;Miro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for brainstorming and graphics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/&#34;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for visualization prototyping&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for internal project discussions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zoom.com/&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for weekly updates with stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Plugin&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moodle development environment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.php.net/&#34;&gt;PHP 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL 15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Debian 12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin development:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.php.net/&#34;&gt;PHP 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mustache.github.io/&#34;&gt;Mustache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/Style/CSS/Overview.en.html&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecma-international.org/publications-and-standards/standards/ecma-262/&#34;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Testing&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://playwright.dev/docs/api/class-test&#34;&gt;Microsoft Playwright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for End-to-End-Tests&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for Gitlab CI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en&#34;&gt;Nodejs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for local execution&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future</title>
      <link>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://showtime.f4.htw-berlin.de/ss25/master/m4-moodle-plugin/future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Starting Point&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        The project was designed to be used in the upcoming semester by our supervisor Prof. Dr. Lucy Weggler. The creation of this plugin was based on her lacking a reliable difficulty label for her large number of math test questions. To generate difficulty labels before this project, she developed a pipeline that extracts key concepts from math questions using a language model, based on the assumption that more concepts indicate higher difficulty. However, this label shows no correlation with the statistical parameters that can be obtained from tasks in Moodle, such as success rates (correct entries).&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            Future Use by Supervisor&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        Over time, the plugins will fill this gap by generating a reliable difficulty label from the student reviews. In the future, the data collected by the plugins will be used to verify the current naive label and replace it with one derived from the student reviews. Ultimately, the data will be used to train a model to take over the complexity estimation.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;section&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;            General Use Cases&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;spacer&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;&#xA;        The plugin suite developed in this project is designed for the entire Moodle community, not just our supervisor. By enabling students to rate the difficulty of test questions, the plugins provide valuable insights into their learning experience. This helps teachers to better understand where their students are struggling or excelling. In courses with varying skill levels in particular, this feedback enables instructors to adapt their teaching focus based on actual student responses, for more effective teaching.&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
